Hello, my name is Adrian Arceo and now we're going to get into some first and third base coaching.
Now, don't think that just because you're not between those two white lines that you're not an important part of the offense, because even the smartest base runners, needs help getting around the bases.
Now, as a first base coach or a third base coach you have to be smart, you have to have a lot of experience, you have to make split second decisions and know the capabilities of not only the players on your team, but the players on the other team.
Now, between the first and third base coaches, there's actually a lot of communication going on, but each individual coach has different responsibilities.
Usually the first base coach is responsible for the runner between home and first base.
As soon as the runner starts heading out to second base, the responsibility gets handed onto the third base coach.
Now as a base coach you have to respond to differences in outs, counts, innings, players, situations and game intensity.
So there's a lot to go into when it comes to coaching third and first base.
And, just as in a game, when an umpire makes a bad call, it can change the entire outcome of the game.
A bad decision or a bad call by the first or third base coaches can actually change the entire game completely.
So don't be fooled, being a first and third base coach is actually very important!